本字幕由 ShinY 深影字幕组 原创翻译制作
深影字幕组论坛地址 http://shinybbs.com
翻译： 小白 JoJo 老贝小春天 红鼻子的UFO Danky Vernie
校对： 小妖怪   后期： Pilar
彼岸是天堂 第二季 第四集
多谢你能来见我 芬顿先生
Thank you for agreeing to meet with me, Mr Fenton.
莫里知道你来这么?
Does Moray know you're here?
不知道 先生 按之前的约定
No, sir. As we agreed,
这场会面只有你知我知
this meeting is between you and I.
我好像还不能走
I can't seem to leave.
总有做不完的事
There's always something else to do.
我只是想为上任的第一天做好准备
I just want to be prepared for my first day.
噢 你行的
Oh, I don't doubt you will be.
你是来祝我好运的?
Have you come to wish me luck?
你要是需要的话
I would, if I thought you needed it.
- 我们如愿以偿了 - 是的 差不多
- We have everything we wished for. - Yes. Almost.
抱歉 艾德蒙 我能帮什么忙?
I'm sorry, Edmund. What could I do?!
我看见门被砸碎了 来里头看看
I saw the door was smashed, had a look inside
却没有人 就只好叫你来了
but I couldn't see anyone. So all I could think of was send for you.
你觉得是谁干的?
Who do you think it was?
窃贼? 不像是偷了很多东西的模样 是吧?
Robbers? Doesn't look like they've taken much, does it?
我经营这家店多少年了
How many years have I taken care of this shop,
从无到有一点点地积累
built it up from nothing?
我的小店 洛维特的帷帐
My shop. Lovett's Drapery.
看这一团糟! 谁会做这事?
Look at this! Who would do this?
是谁闯进来
Who would come in here
这么肆意践踏一个男人的心头肉?!
and not give a care for a man's life?!
我们会整理好的 然后修好门!
We'll tidy it up, get the glass fixed!
再然后我就满心担忧地回到我的小屋去
But then I go back to my cottage with a head full of worries.
那干脆卖了它不就好啦 是不是?
You'll just have to sell it then, won't ya?
是不是林子大了什么鸟都有 山姆?
What kind of people live in this world now, Sam?
德妮丝!
Denise!
我... 我可不会假装这是我人生中
I'm... Look, I'm not going to pretend that this is the happiest
最快乐的一天
day of me life.
我也不会说我觉得这很公平
I'm not going to stand here and say I think it's fair,
因为老实说...
because honestly...
哎呦喂 注意喽 德妮丝 梅尔托在找你呢
Oh, you'd better watch out, Denise. Myrtle's looking for you.
我想她一定给你特制了一份腌鱼
I do believe that she got hold of a kipper especially for you.
我只想告诉你...
Look, I just want you to know that...
噢! 差点忘了 你叔叔回来了
Oh! Nearly forgot. Your uncle's back.
但小店出了点问题
Problem at the shop.
瞧 一直以来我都知道我没希望 就像...
Look, I knew all along I didn't stand a chance, like, so...
早 我都搞不清自己是饿还是不饿了
Morning. I don't know whether I'm hungry or not hungry.
我太激动了 可否亲吻一下女装部主管呢?
I'm so excited. Am I allowed to kiss the Head of Ladieswear?
我永远也不会像你俩那么出色 但是我可以说
I'll never be as fine as you two, but I can say now,
苏西・贝尔 来自女装部
Susy Bell - Ladieswear.
- 那对我来说就够威风了 - 你在这儿!
- Well, that's fine enough for me. - There you are!
我给你煮了一份腌鱼 真他娘的好吃
I have cooked a bloody lovely kipper for you
但要变得真他娘的冷了
and it's going bloody cold.
我马上就去 梅尔托
I'll be along in a minute, Myrtle.
不是因为你有权把我调去店里而奉承你的
I'm not doing this because you're in a position to put me front of house.
我永远不会干这种事
I would never do such a thing.
早 梅尔托! 我也在呢!
Morning, Myrtle! I'm here too!
碰巧手边有腌鱼就做了 就这样而已
Just happened to get me hands on a kipper, that's all.
好吧 在亚瑟向你脱帽致意之前
Well, I'd better say it quick,
我得速战速决
before Arthur comes doffing his cap at you.
我不会为难你 只是 尽量...
Look, I won't make it difficult for you. Just, try and...
我发现真的挺难接受 如果你对我说...
I'd find it really hard if you spoke to me...
克莱拉 我不会一夜之间就变成奥德丽女士
Clara, I'm not going to turn into Miss Audrey overnight.
我保证
I promise.
以后还需要请你多多关照
I'm going to need your help.
可最重要的是 我从来都不想失去你
But most of all, I never want to lose your friendship.
德妮丝! 你的腌鱼!
Denise! Kippers!
我压根就不喜欢腌鱼
I don't even LIKE kippers.
苏西肯定能帮上忙
- I'm sure Susy'll help you out.
你在我店里干什么?
What are you doing in my shop?
听见没? 你在我商店干什么?!
Did you hear me? What are you doing in my shop?!
当时又没人
It was empty.
你打破了门! 看看你做的好事!
You broke the door! Look at the mess you've made!
哪条沟里来的滚回哪去! 你听见没?!
Get back to the gutter you came from! Do you hear me?!
- 上帝保佑你 - 滚蛋!
- God bless you. - Get out!
真是难以置信地乏味 他们谈论的尽是
It's tedious beyond belief. All they talk of is
会热卖的是印花还是条纹
whether prints or stripes will sell,
这个秋天哪种丝绸会热销
what kind of silk might sell this autumn.
爸爸 凯瑟琳跟我说
Papa, Katherine told me how, when she was a girl,
她小时候常常
she used to
跑到森林里去找神秘人
run off into the woods here searching for The Secret People.
神秘人是我想象出来的朋友
The Secret People were my imaginary friends.
对独生子女的孤独的一种慰藉
An only child's compensations for her loneliness.
- 爸爸 我们能... - 沿街扩建店面
- Papa, could we...? - It was Moray's intention
是莫里的主意 没错吧?
to expand along the whole street, wasn't it?
汤姆 亲爱的 芙罗拉在问你问题
Tom, my darling, Flora was asking you a question.
你的问题是什么 芙罗拉?
What is your question, Flora?
我喜欢听凯瑟琳讲她少女时期的故事
I loved hearing about when Katherine was a girl.
你能不能也给我讲讲你年轻的时候
Would you tell me about when you were a boy?
大概可以
Possibly.
我认为我们应该在莫里没做到的点上找突破口
I think we should do what Moray so patently failed to achieve.
我有三个目标 第一个是找机会重返天堂百货
I have three objectives - to find a way back into the store.
- 你做到了 - 是"我们"做到的
- You've done that. - WE'VE done that.
没你里应外合 什么事都完不成
Nothing would be possible without you keeping it together here.
另外两个是 筹集资金 然后劝服
And the other two are, to find the funds, and persuade
- 威斯顿夫妇卖了商店 - 卖给我
- Mr and Mrs Weston to sell. - To sell to me.
莫里先生 达德利先生
Mr Moray. Mr Dudley.
我有个关于女装部促销的建议
I have a proposal for a promotion in Ladieswear.
点子来得挺快啊
You didn't waste much time.
下午茶 实际上 是办个茶宴
Afternoon tea. Indeed, a tea party.
放些桌子 铺上洁白的桌布
Tables. With white tablecloths.
加上茗茶 蛋糕和烤饼
Fine teas. Cakes and scones.
女士们会被吸引进来 然后坐下闲聊...
The ladies would come in, to sit and gossip...
那由谁来上蛋糕和茗茶?
And who would serve the cakes and fine teas?
梅尔托可以
I thought Myrtle.
不错! 你心肠真好 德妮丝
Right! Oh, it is good-hearted of you, Denise.
我们都知道梅尔托唠叨着调到店里来的事
We all know that Myrtle nags away to come front of house.
但是好心肠可不是运作一个部门最需要的品质
But good-heartedness is not the best quality for running a department.
梅尔托绝不能派去服务我们的客户
Myrtle must never be let loose on our customers.
女装部上蛋糕?!
Cakes in Ladieswear?!
你真以为那是我们苦心要塑造的形象吗?
Do you honestly suppose - that is the impression we are trying to make?
不是 先生
No, sir.
就这样吧
No. Right.
事实就这样 德妮丝
It's true, Denise, what he says.
他没说错 你需要立刻进入角色
You need to step into the role now.
那意味着你做的决定可能不招人喜爱
That means making decisions that others won't like.
你必须自信坚定
You have to be strong.
最终 他们一定会尊重你
In the end, they will respect you,
但是一开始
but to begin with,
你不能总担心他们是否喜欢你
you can't let yourself worry whether they'll like you or not.
德妮丝小姐 这些帽子是要展览的吗?
Miss Denise, are these hats to go on display?
是的 苏西 放在窗户旁边
Yes, Susy. Put them by the window.
德妮丝小姐 我该把它们都取出来吗 女士?
Miss Denise, shall I put all of them out, ma'am?
对了! 德妮丝小姐
Oh! Miss Denise,
我是否需要给试衣间添些鲜花?
shall I fetch some fresh flowers for the changing closet?
摆弄鲜花一向是克莱拉喜爱的活
Clara usually likes to do the flowers.
来吧 我们一起去取花
Come on, we'll fetch them together.
德妮丝小姐 梅尔托在找你
Miss Denise, Myrtle's asking for you.
但是你答应了的
But you promised.
我说了我试过了 梅尔托
I said I'd try, Myrtle.
好吧 你没有尽力 对吧?
Well, you didn't try hard enough, did you?
苏西都有了个职位
Susy has a position.
怎么苏西有的我就没有?
What's Susy got that I haven't?
就因为她是你室友 对吗?
She shared a room with you, is that it?
我真的很希望我们依然是朋友
I so want us to remain friends.
朋友? 朋友是这么当的?
Friends? Is that what you call it?
你对我来说是朋友
I know I'm a friend to you.
我就不确定你是否当我是朋友了 因为
I'm not so sure you're a friend to me, now that
你名字后还有个"小姐"尊称呢
you have a Miss before your name.
好了 我还有活要干 德妮丝"小姐"
Well, I have work to do, MISS Denise.
炉子得擦干净
There's stoves to be scrubbed.
这个旧理发店收购了有一年多了是吗?
This old barber's shop was purchased over a year ago, I understand?
是的先生 本是计划着扩展店面用
Yes, sir. I believe the plan was to expand.
那怎么现在是这个样子?
Then why does it stand like this?
莫里先生重新考虑了 先生
Mr Moray reconsidered it, sir.
叫他到这来见我
Ask him to come out here to join me.
恐怕莫里先生这会儿
I'm afraid Mr Moray's
去见我们的供应商了 先生
gone out to meet with one of our suppliers, sir.
- 要多久? - 我不知道
- How long will he be? - I don't know.
也许他约见的不止一个
I think perhaps he is visiting more than one merchant.
那我就等着
Then I will wait.
嘿 看这个老巫婆
Hey, look at this old witch.
从这都能闻到她的味道
Ugh, smell her from here.
你觉得她是要进去买件皮草吗?
Do you think she's coming in to buy a fur?
我们该问问她 给她量量尺寸
We should ask her. Measure her up.
很抱歉当时对你那种态度 我做得太过了
I'm sorry I spoke to you that way. There was no call for that.
你饿吗?
Are you hungry?
你想要的很明显 莫里
It's clear what you want, Moray.
你和我都渴...渴望同样的事
You c-crave the same thing as I do.
威斯顿夫妇挡着咱...咱们的路了
Mr and Mrs Weston stand in the way of b-both of us, do they not?
也许在这件事上我们有着相同的利益
Perhaps you and I may be of benefit to one another in this matter.
这件事怎么行得通 芬顿先生?
How might that be possible, Mr Fenton?
我有资金 你有手...手段
I have the funds. You have the m-means.
你借钱给我?
You would loan me the money?
别急 莫里 先别着急
Slowly, Moray. Slowly. Please.
我会买下天堂百货
I would purchase The Paradise
那么我们就是它的共有者了
and we would become joint owners.
这就是我的提议
That is what I offer.
开诚布公地说
Let us be forthright.
你我都想完全拥有这家百货
Each of us intends to own the store outright.
这场仗就在眼前
That battle lies ahead.
我建议我们彼此都接受这个提议
I suppose each of us would take that on rather than
总好过任凭威斯顿夫妇摆布
be at the mercy of Tom Weston and his wife.
- 不是吗? - 是的
- Is that so? - It is so.
那么如有你能请到一个好律师的话
And if you have the price of a good lawyer,
我们就能达成协议了
we can proceed to an agreement.
那么你觉得我们该如何除掉他们?
And how do you propose we might remove them, sir?
不用我们动手 他们自己就会除掉自己
WE don't. They remove themselves,
只要我们能介入他们之间
if we come between them.
介入他们? 但是我们怎么能做到 先生?
Between them? But how might we do such a thing, sir?
就像我说的
As I say,
我有资金 你有手段
I have the funds, you have the means.
嫉妒
Jealousy.
人都会憎恶他的对手 还不止是憎恶
A man detests a rival, but more than this,
他一定受不那个人和他的妻子眉来眼去
he cannot bear the sight of the man who has enjoyed intimacy with his wife.
我知道了
I see.
我要奚落汤姆・威斯顿
I must taunt Tom Weston.
对凯瑟琳示好 表示出我对她的关心
Show kindness to Katherine. Exhibit concern for her.
并且提醒她 提醒他们俩 我们的亲密关系
And remind her, remind them both of our closeness.
我做不到 先生
I cannot do such a thing, sir.
做不到还是不...不想做?
Cannot or w-will not?
感谢你的考虑 芬顿先生
Thank you for your consideration, Mr Fenton.
我以为你是个认真的人 莫里
I thought you were a serious man, Moray.
我当你是个有目标 有野心的人
I took you for a man of purpose, ambition.
你只要调调情就能拿回你...你的商场
You could have your store back for the sake of a l-little flirting.
可你连玩弄威斯顿夫人都做不到
Yet you find it beyond you to toy with
莫非是出于感情上的原因?
Mrs Weston, perhaps for sentimental reasons?
我的原因我自己清楚就好
My reasons are for me to know.
如果你能重新考虑 我随时为你准备着
If you should reconsider, I'm always available to you.
去吧
Come on.
我相信女装部一切都好 克莱拉
I trust that all is well in Ladieswear, Clara.
既然你问了 先生 我可决不会引起骚乱
Since you ask, sir, far be it for me to cause a stir.
什么?
Yes?
我们相处的很好
We are getting along splendidly.
奥德丽小姐浑身是刺 让大家都心情不好
Miss Audrey had a prickle about her that could make the air sour.
德妮丝小姐总是贴心又开朗
Miss Denise is all sweetness and delight.
不是太贴心 我希望
Not too sweet, I hope.
我不想我们在错误的影响下犯错
I would hate to think we'd made a mistake under the wrong influence.
哪来的错误的影响 先生?
What influence might that be, sir?
德妮丝是莫里的爱人
Denise is Moray's lover.
我相信德妮丝能赢得这个职位是因为她的才能
I choose to believe that Denise won the position because of her talents.
我很钦佩你对人性如此相信 克莱拉
I admire your faith in humanity, Clara.
虽然我不能苟同
Even if I cannot share it.
莫里先生今天去哪了?
Where is Mr Moray today?
我又不是他的记事本 先生
I don't keep his diary, sir.
这不是像我这样的人能知道的
It's not for the likes of me to know.
你怎么了 威斯顿先生?
What is it, Mr Weston?
一会就过去了 你走吧!
It will pass. Go! Be on your way!
我不能让你这么痛苦地一个人在这 先生
I can't leave you here in such pain, sir.
苏西...
Susy...
苏西
Susy.
有客人来了
We have a customer.
他在你的办公室 他在这儿待了一上午了
He's in your office. He's been here all morning.
我不得不编个理由解释你为什么不在这
I had to make up a story to explain why you were not here.
你去哪了?
Where have you been?
威斯顿先生
Mr Weston.
抱歉我没在 我没想到你今天会来
Forgive my absence. We weren't expecting you today.
等了很久了吗 先生?
Have you been waiting long, sir?
你的会面有成效吗?
Did your meeting prove to be fruitful?
这些事还是要小心处理的
These things take delicate handling.
达德利告诉我你和新的客户会面了
Dudley told me you were meeting with new clients.
我有很多会面
I had various meetings.
和我说说那个理发店
Tell me about the barber's shop.
它看着不顺眼
It's an eyesore.
一个运转良好的企业需要持续发展
A well-run enterprise would get on with developing it.
我的计划是把那做成珠宝店
My plan is to use the premises as a jewellery department.
你打算扩建店面吗 先生?
Are you intending to expand, sir?
整个街道 两边都要
The whole street. Both sides.
我要成为
I intend to be the owner
这个国家最大的的百货商场的拥有者
of the largest department store in this country.
你是怎么变成这样的 拉比?
What brought you to a life like this, Ruby?
我本来有个女儿 现在仍然有 我猜
I had a daughter. I still do, I suppose.
她跑了 离开了我
She ran off. Left me.
我生病了
I was ill and,
她那时才15岁 还是个孩子
well, she was only 15, she was still a child.
她是个不负责的家伙 但是你依然要爱她
She's a flighty thing. But you had to love her.
这不是一个女儿该做的事
She's not much of a daughter to do such a thing.
哦 我是她的负担 我知道
Oh, I was a burden to her, I know I was.
一个只能照顾生病母亲的女孩没法生活
A girl can't live only to take care of her sick ma.
我只想告诉她... 我已经好了
I just want to tell her that... that I am on me feet
- 不需要她来照顾我 - 你是在找她吗?
- and she don't have to look after me. - Are you searching for her?
- 我找到她了 - 在这个城市?
- I've found her. In this city?
就在这条街
In this street.
她给我妹妹写信了
She wrote to me sister, and I was
我很高兴她现在能有自己的生活
so glad to hear that the child has a good life for herself now.
她自己的! 连她母亲都不管?
For herself, yeah! Not a care for her mother!
你会原谅你孩子的任何错
Your own bairns can be forgiven anything.
如果你需要这还有很多吃的
There's more food if you want it.
你知道现在什么能让我感觉好点吗?
You know what would help the way I'm feeling?
喝点酒
A little drink.
我只想安抚下我的灵魂
You know, just to soothe the soul a touch.
我一整天都在琢磨 你错了 约翰
It's been on my mind all day. You're wrong, John.
我要在女装部办茶宴的做法才是正确的
My motives for staging the tea party in Ladieswear are the right ones.
我们的顾客最喜欢看别人购物
More than anything, our customers like to see each other shopping.
我要她们产生嫉妒心
I want to feed their jealousies
这样一来她们就会开始闲聊
and the tittle-tattle that comes with them.
如果斯皮罗夫人买了一个带丝带的凉帽
If Mrs Spiro buys the summer hat with ribbons,
那么沃恩夫人也会想要同样的帽子
then Mrs Vaughan wants the same hat.
她们本来想随便逛逛 但是感觉太引人注目了
They try to loiter as it is, but they feel conspicuous,
所以才会离开 我想让她们留下来
so they leave. I want them to stay.
如果有很多女人在看着
If there are tables of women watching,
那么这些购物的女人为了炫耀会购买更多
those who are shopping will buy more in order to show off.
你是对的 对不起
You're right. I'm sorry.
那么是梅尔托来给茶宴服务吗?
And will Myrtle be serving the tea?
她要做的就是给每个桌子端端盘子
All she will have to do is take a tray to each table.
我不能让我的人做这些
I can't ask my girls to do it.
那就放手去做吧
Then by all means go ahead.
汤姆・威斯顿想要扩张商场
Tom Weston is intent on expanding the store.
这难道不是件好事吗?
But that's a good thing, isn't it?
不 对我们来说不是
No, not for us it isn't.
我绞尽脑汁地想办法来筹集资金
I've been racking my brains to find a way to raise the funds to
买下目前的天堂百货
buy The Paradise as it stands.
如果他沿街建更多的店铺
If he builds more, builds along the street,
就超出我的能力范围了
it will be beyond my reach.
我以为我会有时间 但我没有了
I thought I had time on my side. I don't.
德妮丝 如果我能找到办法现在就行动 马上
Denise, if I was to find a way to act now, soon,
如果这个办法有风险...
if it was precarious....
你必须把握机会 约翰 一定要
You must take it, John. You must.
我们得让你试试新制服 梅尔托
We'll need to get you fitted for a new uniform, Myrtle,
如果你要在女装部端茶倒水的话
if you're to be serving tea and cakes in Ladieswear.
娘的我就知道 我就说德妮丝不会让我们失望
I bloody knew it! I said Denise would not let us down.
姑娘们 姑娘们 我有好消息
Girls! Girls! Wait until you hear about this!
你忘了自己的身份 德妮丝小姐
Oh, you're forgetting yourself, Miss Denise.
你的桌子在那边
Your table's over there.
没人介意的话 我跟朋友坐一起
I'll sit with my friends, if no-one minds.
真搞不懂你叔叔 德妮丝
There's no fathoming your uncle, Denise.
有人闯进了他的商店 搞得一片狼藉
His shop is broken into, the place is a mess.
他找到了那个犯事的流浪女
He finds some tramp woman who's responsible,
发誓要掐死她 可后来我再见到他
swears he'll strangle her. The next time I see him
他正带着那个流浪者去他的店里安身了
he's escorting the very same vagabond into his shop for shelter.
一定是我们在街上见到的老巫婆
Must be that old witch we saw on the street,
苏西 你叫她什么来着
Susy. What did you call her?
无牙老太婆 这里都能闻到她的味儿
Toothless hag. Smell her from here.
今天我问莫里昨天他在哪儿 他为什么要撒谎
Why would Moray lie to me about where he was today?
这重要吗
Why does it matter?
重要 因为他有事隐瞒
It matters because he has something to hide.
亲爱的 没有什么秘密可言
My darling, there is no secret.
莫里不是回来顺从我们想法的
Moray did not come back to serve our purpose.
他是打算从我们手中夺走天堂百货的
He intends to try to wrest The Paradise from us.
他到处奔走想借点钱
He has been scurrying around trying to borrow money,
但是没人会考虑他
but no-one will so much as consider him.
我已经确定过了
I have made sure of that.
爸爸的银行朋友知道如果有人
Papa's banking friends know I would be
把莫里当回事儿 我会非常生气的
most upset if any of them so much as considered Moray for a meeting.
那他今天去见谁了
Then who was his engagement with today?
- 太漂亮了 - 你拿着它干什么?
- It's so beautiful! - What are you doing with that?
你能穿上吗 求你啦
Will you put it on? Please.
你从哪儿拿的 从哪儿拿的?!
Where did you get it? Where did you get it?!
芙罗拉一天到晚都缠着我
All day, every day, Flora keeps asking me
让我讲你年轻时候的事 我想她...
questions about when you were younger. I thought she...
你绝不能碰我的东西
You NEVER touch my belongings!
知道"绝不"是什么意思吗
Do you know what "never" means?!
永远都不能
It means NOT EVER!
你爸爸不是有意的 宝贝
Your papa did not mean to be so harsh, darling girl.
他只是一时没缓过来 就是这样 是我的错
You shocked him, that's all. It's my fault.
也许那件上衣承载了他的记忆
Perhaps that tunic has memories for him.
战争的记忆
Memories of the war.
这是我的错 让我来弥补吧
I made a mistake. Let me make it up to you.
我们来弥补下 你和我 就在早上
We'll have a treat. You and I. In the morning.
我们做些什么 去骑马吗
What shall we do? Shall we go riding?
- 或者去野餐 - 去天堂百货
- Perhaps a picnic? - The... The Paradise.
没错 我们去天堂百货
Yes. We'll go to The Paradise
去好好放纵一下
and we will indulge ourselves.
晚安 苏西
Good night, Susy.
你在这儿干什么
WHAT are you doing here?
- 我来看你 孩子 - 我不希望你在这儿
- I've come to see you, child. - I don't want you here.
你不能给你妈一个道歉的机会吗?
Can you not give your ma a chance to say that she's sorry?
道歉 我应该相信吗?
"Sorry"? Am I supposed to believe that?
这么多年 你就想说句对不起吗?
All these years and that's all you want "sorry"?
我一直在找你
I've been looking for you.
我没那么难找 贝拉姑姑知道我在哪儿
I'm not so hard to find. Aunt Bella knows where I am.
我没有一天不在想我的女儿
There's not a day goes by where I don't think about my girl!
要我告诉你我怎么想的吗?
Shall I tell you what I think of?
我自己的声音祈求你不要离开我 不要让我走
My own voice pleading with you not to leave me, not to let me go.
我亲妈却喝得太醉听不到
And my own mother too drunk to hear me.
甚至不会亲我
Too drunk to even KISS me.
我现在有了自己的生活 而你不在其中
I have a life now, and you are no part of it!
跟我进去 来吧 跟我进去坐坐
Come inside with me. Come on. Come and sit with me.
让你妈妈好好看看你 就一晚
Let your ma feast her eyes on her beautiful girl just for one night.
坐在一起看你喝酒
Sit with you while you drink,
听你讲故事骗我让我相信你不算坏吗
tell me some story that will trick me into believing you're not so bad?
我妈妈对我撒谎 一向如此 她满嘴谎话
My mother lied to me. That's what she does, she lies.
你去喝吧 妈
You go and drink, Ma.
喝了多少瓶才会忘了自己曾有个女儿?!
How many glasses till you forget you even HAVE a daughter?!
你去喝个够吧
You... you go and drink your fill.
如果你还有慈悲之心
If you have any mercy,
今晚就沿着这条街一直走
you will walk down that street tonight
永远不要回来
and NEVER come back!
有些事情我们自认为无法承受
There are things we believe we cannot bear.
但其实我们可以
But we can bear them.
我们可以承受
We do bear them.
早上好
Morning.
我们得让你女儿看到最好的你
We need your daughter to see you looking at your best,
让她知道你病好了 恢复了
if she's to know you're back on your feet and well again.
你人真好
That is kind of ya.
你可以去后面洗漱一下
You can wash and clean up in the back.
这是我最爱的颜色
It's me favourite colour.
我已经很多年没穿过新的漂亮的衣服了
It's many years since I wore a dress new and pretty.
拉比 我得回到我妻子身边了
Ruby, I need to be getting back to my wife.
我们刚结婚 在海边有一间小屋
I'm newly married. We have a cottage by the sea.
我不能呆在这儿了 所以我怎么安排你好呢?
I can't stay here. So what are we to do with you?
我没地方去
I've nowhere to go.
你女儿呢 跟她谈过了吗?
What about your daughter? If you talk to her?
我会穿上这衣服 让我看起来精神点
I'll put the dress on and I'll smart meself up.
她会看到我不再那么体弱多病了
And she will see that I'm not sickly no more.
你确定你没事吗?
Are you sure you're well enough?
如果我能留下 直到和她说话
If I could stay until such time as I speak with her.
我想保持最好的状态
I would like to be at my best.
当然 你当然可以
Course. Course you can.
乔纳斯
Jonas!
我想和你谈谈
I want to talk with you.
汤姆・威斯顿在考虑...
Tom Weston is considering...
他打算扩张商店 先生
He intends to develop the store, sir.
如果我要求进一步与芬顿先生谈谈
If I were to request further discussions with Mr Fenton...
如果您愿意的话 我可以今天为你安排 先生
I could arrange that for you today, if you wish, sir.
或只是给他带个信
Or I could simply convey a message to him
说您愿意重新考虑他的要求
saying you're willing to reconsider his offer.
如果您真的愿意重新考虑
If you are indeed willing to reconsider his proposition?
我们如何
How would we, er...?
威斯顿先生是个反复无常的人
Mr Weston is a volatile man, sir.
他做事比较轻率
He is capable of behaving rashly.
甚至粗暴
Wildly, even.
那你猜他会轻率地解雇我还是粗暴地摆脱我?
Suppose he rashly dismisses me, or wildly decides to get rid of me?
让我说的话 先生
If I may, sir,
他的妻子不会让这一切发生的
his wife would not permit that to happen.
是 是 我明白
Yes. Yes, I understand.
您需要我去联系芬顿先生吗
Do you wish me to contact Mr Fenton, sir?
是的
I do.
我要让大家看看...
I will show 'em all...
我要让莫里先生知道他错了 让达德利先生
I'll show Mr Moray he was wrong. I'll show Mr Dudley
知道我真正的模样
what I am truly made of.
我看起来美吧 本就这样
Well, don't I look pretty? Made for it.
管好你的嘴 不然大家都跟你一起丢人
Well, just watch your mouth or you'll put us all to shame.
德妮丝 随她去吧
Denise! Erm, leave her be.
她准备好了会来找你的
She'll come to you when she's ready to.
威斯顿夫人 芙罗拉小姐
Mrs Weston! Miss Flora.
什么风把您二位吹来了
What brings you to see us today?
我打算让芙罗拉今早好好玩玩
I am intent on spoiling Flora this morning.
那您来对地方了 夫人
Then you have come to the right place, ma'am.
你将享受我们最棒的服务
You shall receive only the finest service from our ladies,
我向您保证
I can assure you.
威斯顿夫人
Mrs Weston.
呃 凯瑟琳 抱歉 我忘乎所以了
Er, Katherine. Forgive me, I forgot myself.
您今天非常美丽动人
May I say how lovely you look today?
我的意思是 商店的大门永远向你敞开
What I mean is, it's always a delight to see you in the store.
还有你 芙罗拉小姐
And you, Miss Flora.
凯瑟琳 既然你来了
Since you're here, Katherine,
可以和我一起喝杯咖啡吗?
perhaps you'll join me
还有你的丈夫 如果他也来了的话
for coffee. And your husband, if he is to visit us today?
你今天心情很好啊 莫里
You're in fine spirits today, Moray.
我承蒙你的关照
I owe you the courtesy of kindness.
虽然你没有必要非得答应
You do not owe me any such consideration,
但如果有这机会我会很感激
but I'd be grateful for the chance to earn your forbearance.
我很高兴和你一起喝咖啡
I'd be delighted to join you for coffee.
芙罗拉!
Flora!
加了肉桂的咖啡
Coffee. With cinnamon.
威斯顿夫人 女士 芙罗拉小姐
Mrs Weston. Ma'am. Miss Flora.
我希望你今天尽管宠着芙罗拉 德妮丝
I want you to utterly spoil Flora today, Denise.
她想要什么就给她什么
Anything she wants, she can have.
这是我们的荣幸 夫人
It would be our pleasure, ma'am.
苏西 请招待这位年轻的女士
Susy, please attend to the young lady.
我和莫里喝咖啡的这段时间 她就交给你了
I will leave it with you while I have a coffee with Moray.
我想要一件这种有羽毛的衣服
I want one of these dresses with the feathers.
恐怕这些礼服是给大人穿的 小孩不能穿
I'm afraid these gowns are for adults, not children.
但我想要
But I want one.
让我给你看一些
Let me show you some of the things
更适合小女孩的东西
we have that might be more suitable for a girl.
我设想了一下把扩展区建成珠宝部的事
I had myself thought of making the extension a jewellery department.
我想象客人们在街道上走时
I imagined that as customers approached along the street
他们最先看到的
the first thing they would see
是充满了贵气和色彩的橱窗
would be windows bursting with colours and extravagance.
但光是储存展品的费用就超出了我的预算
But the cost of stocking the display alone was beyond me.
不过 现在情况不同了
However, things are different now.
咖啡还可以吗 凯瑟琳?
How's your coffee, Katherine?
不错 很美味
It's fine. It's delicious.
我第一次发现肉桂咖啡是在 呃
I first discovered cinnamon coffee whilst in, erm,
印度 对吧 凯瑟琳?
was it India, Katherine?
- 不 不 我想是摩洛哥 - 是在锡兰
- No, no, no, I think it was Morocco. - It was Ceylon.
对 对 我费尽口舌才说服凯瑟琳尝尝
Yes, yes! I had the devil to convince Katherine to try it,
但她喝过一次之后 就再也喝不够了
but once she did, she could never have enough.
你喝咖啡的时候还会放肉桂吗? 凯瑟琳
Do you still drink your coffee with cinnamon, Katherine?
- 有时候会 - 是的 她会
- Sometimes. - Yes, she does.
我已经找到了红宝石和绿宝石的供货商
I've already sourced suppliers for rubies and emeralds, if you'd
你希望我叫他们带着样品和报价来拜访我们吗
care for me to have them call on us with samples and prices,
威斯顿先生?
Mr Weston?
我计划所有的柜台都用玻璃来制作
I'd planned for all the counters to be made of glass.
还有吊灯 玻璃灯 整个商场要像宫殿一样
And chandeliers, glass lamps, the whole place is like a palace.
闪亮的东西多了会显得太花哨
So much dazzle sounds positively garish.
是啊 或许你是对的 先生
Yes, well, perhaps you're right, sir.
我希望你旅行之后睡眠质量有所改善 凯瑟琳
I hope your sleep has improved after your travels, Katherine.
我曾告诉她是因为咖啡的作用 但她不听劝
I used to tell her it's the coffee, but she wouldn't have it.
如果女人可以不睡觉地活着...
If ever a woman could live without sleep...
我曾被迫在花园里度过漫长的一夜
I was pressed into spending long nights in the garden.
嗅着月光下木兰花香
The scent of magnolias under the moon...
我觉得扩展区应该做成餐厅
I think the new extension should be a food hall,
或卖鞋 或一些不带感情色彩的东西
or shoes or something without sentiment.
我本来打算和你一起看看那里 莫里
I had meant to look over the place with you, Moray.
但你当时不在 我们现在去看吧
But you were elsewhere. Let's take a look now.
好 当然
Yes, of course,
只是我不想把你的妻子单独留在这喝咖啡
although I would not wish to leave your wife with her coffee.
我准备好走了
I am ready now.
- 我要那双银色的鞋 - 我解释过了
- I want the silver shoes. - As I have explained,
我们没有你的尺码 小姐
we don't have your size, miss.
这双 我要这条带羽毛的裙子
These ones. I want the dress with the feathers.
你不能穿这条有羽毛的裙子
You can't have the dress with the feathers.
但那是我想要的
But that's what I want!
妈妈说我想要什么都可以
Mama said I could have anything I wanted.
你就是个被宠坏的无关紧要的人 这就是你
Oh, you're just a spoiled little NOTHING, that's what you are!
你招招手 全世界都要围着你转!
You wave your hand and the rest of the world is supposed to pamper you!
你想过没有?! 你是个小孩!
Do you even give a thought?! YOU ARE A CHILD!
苏西 下楼去饭厅 马上!
Susy, go down to the refectory right now!
快点 苏西! 下去
Come on, Susy! Go on.
我要妈妈
I want Mama.
我很抱歉 芙罗拉小姐 让我...
I am so sorry, Miss Flora. Let me...
不! 我要妈妈! 我要妈妈!
No! I want Mama! I want Mama!
我很抱歉 夫人 不知道为什么...
I'm so sorry, ma'am. I don't know why...
苏西一向是那样亲切的女孩!
Susy is usually such a sweet girl!
我从来不知道她会... 她是我们的朋友
I've never before known her to... She's a friend,
她平时那么善良又十分殷勤
usually full of kindness and so eager to please.
达德利 请你把芙罗拉带出去一下好吗?
Dudley, do you think you could take Flora outside for a moment for me, please?
当然 夫人
Of course, ma'am.
你准备怎么处理这事?
What do you propose to do?
我会和莫里先生和达德利先生讲...
I will speak to Mr Moray and Mr Dudley...
不 我想知道你准备怎么做
No. I want to know what YOU intend to do.
你是女装部主管 不是吗?
You're Head of Ladieswear, are you not?
你要负责
You ARE responsible.
是你让我的孩子受到如此羞辱
It was you who presided over this humiliation of my child.
这个孩子!
THIS child!
你准备怎么处理这个人?
What do you propose to do about this girl?
- 她叫什么名字? - 苏西 夫人
- What is her name? - Susy, ma'am.
那回答我 你的打算是什么?
Then answer me, what is your intention?
我会跟苏西严肃说明
I will speak with Susy MOST severely.
我会警告她对顾客这种态度...
I will warn her that to address customers in this way...
我们不能做些什么吗?
Can we not do something?
一定有什么原因使苏西...
There must be a reason Susy was...
是有原因 她提升得太早了 她还没准备好
There IS a reason. Susy was promoted too early. She's not ready.
但我们一定可以做点什么!
But there must be something we can do!
现在是紧要关头 德妮丝
These are the most delicate of times, Denise.
我承受不起凯瑟琳的怒火
I cannot afford to rile Katherine.
我们必须顺着她意愿
We must be seen to follow her will.
这是你的工作 德妮丝 你必须这么做
It's your job now, Denise. This has to be done.
你想要这职位 这职位可不是办办茶宴就行
You wanted this position. It's not all tea parties.
我试过了 苏西
I tried, Susy.
我也不想这样
I wanted to avoid this.
但你的所作所为使我没有退路
But what you did, you've left me with no choice.
员工被解雇的时候必须马上离开宿舍
When a girl is dismissed, she must leave the premises right away.
你必须收拾好行李... 然后走
You must collect your belongings... and go.
或许别走远了 苏西
Perhaps stay close by, Susy.
我们不知道会不会有变数
We never know what might change.
我无处可去了
I have nowhere to stay.
毕夏普街 迈希尔先生
Bishop Street. Mr Myhill.
告诉他  乔纳斯・弗兰克斯说
Tell him jonas Franks said
你跟着他或许有个住处
you might find lodgings with him.
蛋糕 夫人?
Cakes, madam?
我像个女人吗?!
Do I look like a madam to you?!
还有 我看这个更像脆骨而不是蛋糕
And THAT looks more like gristle to me than a cake.
我在练习 您要茗茶吗? 还是阿萨姆茶?
I'm practising. Fine teas? Assam?
大吉岭茶呢? 马德拉蛋糕呢?
Darjeeling? Madeira cake?
我表现得还不赖吧?!
Aren't I the picture of restraint?!
德妮丝!
Denise!
德妮丝! 他们都明白苏西是自己引火上身
Denise! They all know that Susy brought this on herself.
他们只是在演戏
Their reactions are for show.
相互证明他们是亲信 他们在反抗我们
To prove to each other they are cronies. Them against us.
这不是长久的 这是恐惧 仅此而已
It won't last. It's fear, that's all.
你现在对他们的生活有影响了
You have influence on their lives now.
你要表现得不是你的错
Act as though you're not to blame. Don't apologise
别为你的所作所为道歉 让他们说去吧
for what you've done. Let them raise the matter if they want. Not you.
表现得你有你的威严
Behave as though you take on your authority
但他们要对自己的命运负责
but they are responsible for their own destiny.
谢谢你 达德利先生
Thank you, Mr Dudley.
你知道这事不怪你 不是吗 德妮丝?
You do know you're not to blame, don't you, Denise?
但我本可以做更多的
But I might have done more.
我看到苏西有什么烦心事
I saw there was something the matter with Susy.
我希望我可以说一切都会好起来的
I wish I could say that it gets easier.
克莱拉 有人看见你和威斯顿先生在海湾
Clara. You were seen in the bays with Mr Weston.
你就是这样看我的吗?
Oh! Is that what you think of me?
只要是穿着西装的男人我就会对他抛媚眼
Any man in a suit and I'll flutter me eyes
然后掀起自己的裙摆吗?
and lift me skirts?
他想从你身上得到什么?
What did he want with you?
他让我把他的名字
He asked to put his name
写在最后那首华尔兹的舞伴卡上
on me dance card for the last waltz,
但我告诉他我已经有约了
but I told him I was all spoken for.
那我不得不叫莫里先生来问你
Then I have no option but to ask
为什么你会握着威斯顿先生的手
Mr Moray to ask you why you were holding Mr Weston's hand.
他那时背痛
He had a pain in his back.
非常痛
Terrible pain.
而他的眼里却不止是痛苦
Something in his eyes. Something more than pain.
- 他看起来就像... - 像什么?
- He looked like a man who'd... - Yes?
像被人谋杀然后在等待死亡
Well, like a man who'd been murdered and was waiting to die,
就像...
it was the same as...
继续说下去克莱拉 你快说完了
Go on, Clara. You're almost done now.
就像看烟火的那晚一样
It was the same as the night of the fireworks.
它的噪音
The noise of it.
让他像吓坏的小孩蜷缩着
He was cowering like a frightened child.
乔纳斯先生 感觉不错吧?
Will that do you, Mr Jonas?
又窥探到世上另一个阴暗的角落
Feel better now you've peered into another dark corner of this world?
谢谢你 克莱拉
Thank you, Clara.
当你对我隐瞒事情时
When you hide things from me, it is
就是你想逃避这些事
because you prefer not to face them yourself.
和乔纳斯躲躲闪闪的
Skulking around with Jonas.
跟凯瑟琳调情 嘲弄汤姆・威斯顿
Flirting with Katherine. Taunting Tom Weston.
发生什么事了?
What's going on?
无论你在做些什么
Whatever it is you are doing,
我都知道你有多么想要回百货
I know how much you want this store back,
但如果你的计划
but if your schemes
对得起良心的话 你会告诉我的
can be admitted in good conscience, then you will tell me.
莫里先生 你有消息要带去贝尔维尔大厅么?
Mr Moray, sir, you wanted a message taking out to Bellville Hall?
今天不了 亚瑟 下次吧
Not today, Arthur. Perhaps some other time.
德妮丝女士
Miss Denise...
乔纳斯 拜托请叫我德妮丝
Please, Jonas, call me Denise.
我更想尊重
I prefer to honour the tradition that has been
流传了那么多年的传统
observed down the years.
这是你赢得的 小姐 这个头衔代表着尊重
You've earned your place, ma'am, the title is a gesture of respect.
好吧 谢谢你
Yes. Well, thank you.
恕我直言...
If I may...
对于我们这种地方 忠诚很重要
there is much talk of loyalty in a place like this.
没有比它更重要的
Most of it is talk and no more.
我真的不希望苏西...
I had no wish for Susy to...
小姐 请让我说下去 忠诚像是特别的礼物
Please, ma'am, let me go on. Loyalty is a special gift.
是唯一能做到凝聚人心的 但需要你鼓起勇气
It binds people like no other cause. But it CAN take courage.
如果你找得到办法让苏西复职
If you can find a way to win Susy her place back here in the store,
你就证明了
you would have proven that you're
你是这里所有员工的忠诚伙伴
the staunchest ally of everyone who works here.
你会变成他们权益的捍卫者
You would be their champion.
但这不可能啊
It is not possible.
不是你亲口和莫里先生说
Was it not you yourself told Mr Moray
"这必须可能"的吗?
it must be possible?
但我不知道该怎么做
But I don't know how.
我也不知道 小姐
Nor do I, ma'am.
但我相信你会想到方法的
But I trust you'll find a way.
杜松子酒
Gin.
没想到会在这里见到你
I didn't expect to see you here.
真希望我也能这么说 妈
I wish I could say the same of you, Ma.
我留下来是想和你再谈一下
I stayed so that I might speak with you one more time.
苏西我不怪你恨我
I don't blame you for hating me, Susy.
把自己的孩子送走一定是世上最严重的罪
It has to be the worst crime in the world to give your child away.
我知道你不会相信我
I know you don't believe me,
但我是为了你才这么做的
but I did it for you.
你怨我的理由
The reasons you use to blame me
就是我不得不送走你的原因
are the reasons that i had to give you away.
跟着我这样的妈妈你会过怎样的生活?
What kind of life would you have with a ma like me?
每天我都告诉自己不能再喝醉
Every day I promise myself I won't be drunk,
但是每天都会发现自己手中又拿着酒杯
and then every day I find meself with a glass in me hand.
我不得不放手让你离开我
I had to free you from me and the only way that
又继续再喝酒
I could do that was to have another drink inside me.
我是对你撒了谎
I have lied to you, yes.
但你老实回答我 你如果留在我身边
But you tell me, if you can tell the truth, would it've been
会比现在过的好么?
a better life if you'd stayed with me than the one that you've had?
不 不会
No. No, it wouldn't.
我人生里唯一能给你的
There's only one thing in this life that I could give you
就是放手让你离开我
and that was to be free of me.
虽然我知道 或许有那么一天
I knew, though, that there'd come the day
我可以看着你
when I'd look at ya...
告诉你我爱你
..and I'd tell ya I love you.
我... 我爱你 妈妈
I... I love you, Ma.
我为你能在那种地方工作而骄傲
I'm so proud of you working in that place.
那儿多豪华
It's so grand.
我不在那里工作了
I don't work there no more.
- 为什么? - 我被解雇了 自找的
- Why? - I was sacked. Made a disgrace of myself.
不会的 我的苏西不会的
No, not you. Not my Susy.
我冒犯了一个小孩
I offended a child.
天啊 他们就没点宽容的心吗?!
Oh, have they no mercy?!
他们该有多卑鄙啊?!
What kind of swines are they?!
不是的... 都过去了 妈妈
No, it... it's done now, Ma.
我再去拿杯酒
I'm just going to get one more.
女儿认回我可不是天天都有的事
It's not every day you get your daughter back.
干杯
Cheers.
让他们下地狱去
Well, to hell with them.
他们都不值得我用口水吐他们
They're not worth a spit
竟能对我女儿做这样的事
if they'd do that to my girl.
我现在在干嘛?
What am I doing?
我为了什么要和你坐在一起?
What am I doing here sitting here with you?
没有变 你什么都没变 还是酒 够了!
It's the same, it's always the same, the drink, that's all!
苏西! 苏西!
Susy! Susy!
夫人 午安 您是想喝阿萨姆茶呢?
Good afternoon, madam. Assam?
还是大吉岭茶?
Darjeeling?
苏西你到这干嘛?
Susy, what are you doing here?
哦 我忘了!
Oh! I forgot!
我... 我急着回家却忘了我不住在这了
I... I was hurrying home and I forgot I don't live here no more.
噢 你最好在乔纳斯先生看到你前离开
Oh, you best go, girl, before Mr Jonas finds ya.
苏西不要走 我有话想跟你说
Susy! Don't go! I want to speak to you.
你想复职么?
Do you want your position back?
我是说 你想试着争取复职么?
What I mean is, do you want to try and get it back?
当然
I should say so.
我不敢保证一定会成功 这需要我们鼓起勇气
I can't promise we'll manage it, it'll take courage.
你可以按我说的做么?
Will you do exactly as I say?
明早的第一件事就是
Then first thing tomorrow morning,
穿上你最好的衣服在街上等我
put on your finest outfit and meet me in the street.
威斯顿夫人
Mrs Weston.
夫人 谢谢你肯见我们
Thank you for seeing us, ma'am.
这么唐突地打扰你我很抱歉
I'm sorry to intrude upon you in this way,
但 夫人 我希望能和您谈谈
but if we might speak with you for a few minutes...
在和芙罗拉小姐发生不愉快的那天
Ma'am, on the day of these embarrassing events with
苏西当时很痛苦
Miss Flora, Susy was in a state of considerable distress.
我不该让她值班的
It was my fault she was on duty.
我该让她休息的
I should have excused her.
那天苏西的妈妈突然出现在街上 她从...
Susy's mother turned up on the street. She hasn't seen her since she was...
从我七岁起就没再见过我妈妈
Since I was seven years old.
她妈妈意外地出现...
It was an unexpected arrival...
苏西还发现她的妈妈处境很糟糕
Susy found her mother in awful circumstances.
所以 夫人 我们恳求
We're asking, ma'am,
苏西能有次机会向芙罗拉小姐道歉
that Susy be given the opportunity to apologise to Miss Flora and the
和证明她值得您的再次信任
chance to prove to you that she's worthy of your trust in the future.
- 您的宽恕... - 宽恕?!
- Your mercy... - Mercy?!
你真觉得我该原谅她?
You think I should forgive her?
芙罗拉小姐 我真心为我所说的话道歉
I am truly sorry for what I said to you, Miss Flora.
每个孩子都不应得到这样的对待
No child should be spoken to so cruelly.
我只想向你道歉
I only want to say I am sorry.
这就是我来的原因 没别的
That is why I am here. No more.
请你原谅她吧 妈妈
Please forgive her, Mama.
你跑去跟凯瑟琳・格伦德宁说之前
You might have asked before you ran off to speak with
应该先来问我 德妮丝
Katherine Glendenning, Denise.
是你自己说的我们要跟她搞好关系
You said yourself we must keep good relations with her.
即便她拒绝了我们的请求
Even if she'd said no to our pleas,
我们也得向她表示悔悟和尊敬
we would have shown her contrition and respect.
是啊 是啊 当然
Yes. Yes, of course.
威斯顿
Weston.
她现在是威斯顿夫人了
Her name is Mrs Weston now.
我不是那么说的吗?
Isn't that what I said?
姑娘们
Girls.
谢谢 德妮丝
Thank you, Denise.
- 他娘的给她们看看 梅尔托 - 我会的
- Bloody show 'em, Myrtle. - I will.
- 他娘的给她们都看看 - 会的
- Bloody show 'em all. - I will.
你看起来很漂亮 梅尔托
You look so lovely, Myrtle.
对 可不是嘛
I do, don't I?
她们坐好了
They're ready.
- 我不行! 我做不了! - 你当然可以
- I can't! I can't do it! - Of course you can.
只是给一些爱闲言碎语的时髦女人上茶而已
It's only serving tea to a few posh gossips.
我这样的人怎么能站在她们面前呢
How can the likes of me stand before the likes of them?
她们这么漂亮
They're so beautiful.
你也很漂亮 梅尔托
You're the one who's beautiful, Myrtle.
不 我不漂亮 站她们旁边我像块破布
No, I'm not. I'm a rag next to them.
我只适合在农场工作 这个我做不了
I'm fit for the farmyard. I can't do it.
对不起 德妮丝
I'm sorry, Denise.
梅尔托
Myrtle.
我还记得男士们排队理发的场景
I remember the queues of men standing waiting for a haircut.
- 乔纳斯 - 威斯顿先生
- Jonas. - Mr Weston, sir.
- 你不舒服? - 旧伤发作了
- You have pain? - It's an old wound.
我告诉自己忽略疼痛 但还是感受的到
I tell myself I should feel no pain. But there is.
我是个傻子
I am a fool.
每当感受到疼痛
Whenever I feel it,
我就斥责自己说这是我的弱点
I chide myself it is weakness.
人们害怕我 因...
People fear me, bec...
请原谅 先生 我多嘴了
Forgive me, sir, I am speaking out of turn.
没有 继续说
Not at all, go on.
我有残疾 人们因此害怕我
I have a disfigurement, people fear me because of it.
但这是个礼物
But it is a gift.
我到了这个年纪才意识到这一点
I have realised that at my age.
那些畏惧一个独臂者的人
People who flinch from a man with one arm
因他们所见而断想他们了解我
imagine they know me, know the worst of me
了解我最坏的一面
because of what they see.
这只会让我知道什么人可以信任
That just tells me whom I can trust.
这是件好事 去找回那些
It is a fine thing, sir, to restore that which has been
完全被忽视了东西
so sorely disregarded.
我向你脱帽致敬 尽管我没有戴帽子
I take my hat off to you. Even though I'm not wearing one.
你觉得我该如何处理它呢 乔纳斯
What do you think I should do with it, Jonas?
我觉得我无法胜任
Oh, I do not think I can be trusted
替您做这么大的决定 先生
with the likes of such a decision, sir.
我相信你
I trust you.
也许可以卖食品 先生 各式面包和馅饼
Perhaps food, sir. Breads and pies and buns.
它们的香味会弥漫在街上
The smell of it on the street.
我想我可以... 给你讲故事
I thought I might... read to you.
- 你想要听我讲故事吗 - 好的 爸爸
- Would you like me to read to you? - Yes, Papa.
从前有一个士兵
There was a soldier.
一个年轻的军官
A young officer.
他驻扎在印度
He was stationed in India.
德里发起了一场攻城战
And there was a siege. At Delhi.
你知道什么是攻城战吗
Do you know what a siege is?
攻城战就是...
Well, a siege is, erm...
就是一种...
It's a kind of...
...攻击
...attack.
死了很多人
Lots of men died.
听我说 苏西 对于一个母亲来说
Let me tell you how it is, Susy. For a mother.
要做很多艰难的抉择
There are hard choices to be made.
你不原谅她 她就无法原谅自己
She can't forgive herself until you forgive her.
她的所作所为不可原谅
What she did was unforgivable.
任何事都能被原谅
Nothing is unforgivable.
而如果你抓着她不放的话
But you'll be bitter
你余后的人生会更痛苦 充满怨恨
and filled with hatred the rest of your life if you don't let go of her.
是她抓着我不放
It's HER that won't let go of me.
- 我该对她说什么 - 说实话
- What would I say to her? - The truth.
带着你对她的一点爱
With a bit of love in it.
他们让你回来了
They took you back, then.
- 他们让我回来了 - 这就对了
- They took me back. - It's only right.
如果你说的都是真的 妈妈
If it's true what you said, Ma,
你想给我一个机会
that you want to give me
从此摆脱你 那就现在吧
a chance to be free of you, then do it now.
让我摆脱你 我会因此而爱你
Do it and I will love you for it.
我只想让你亲一下我的脸颊
I only want one kiss on the cheek.
如果哪天你清醒了
If there is a time when you are sober,
我会在这里
I will be here.
那时候你就能回来了
There's the time you can come back.
茶宴非常成功
The tea party was a splendid success.
谢谢
Thank you.
每当我想告诉你我的想法
When I came to you with my idea,
总觉得无论我想说什么 你都会反对
it felt as though whatever I brought to you, you wanted to turn it down.
你说得轻巧
It was simply the way you presented it.
一旦我看到效益 我会同意的 不是吗
Once I saw the benefits, I consented, didn't I?
你同意了吗 你没有...
You consented?! You didn't...
我要求的只不过是...
All that I ask is...
我知道我们在一起工作会非常艰难...
I see how difficult this is going to be for us, working together...
但我来找你的时候
But when I come to you,
我不是德妮丝 我不是你的未婚妻
I'm not Denise, I'm not your fiancee.
我是女装部的主管
I am Head of Ladieswear.
你知道那该是什么样吗
Can you see that's how it has to be?
是的 是的 当然知道
Yes. Yes. Of course.
对不起 德妮丝 我为我之前的行为道歉
I'm sorry, Denise, for the way I have been.
为苏西的事和拜访凯瑟琳的事
For the way I spoke to you about Susy and about visiting Katherine.
就该这样 这是你的职责
That's how it has to be. That's your job.
我本该告诉你我要去见她
I should have told you I was going to see her,
但是我怕你会制止我
but I was afraid you would refuse me.
我什么时候才能懂 没有秘密
When will I learn? No secrets!
我们不能让任何事横亘在我们之前
We cannot let anything come between us, Denise.
为什么那些事会横亘在我们之间
Why would anything come between us?
我想让你沉浸在我的爱里
I want to shower you with love,
珍爱你
and treasure you.
这才我的职责
That is my job.
我爸爸的手表
My father's watch?
对我来说它是无价之宝
It is precious to me beyond reckoning.
那个手表有魔力 催眠的魔力
That watch has powers. Hypnotic powers.
我可以爱上一个像你那样的男生
I could fall for a lad like you.
苏西一直跟着我缠着我
I've got Susy following me around like a sop,
无论我怎么做 都摆脱不了她
I can't shake her out of it, no matter what I do!
你把它放口袋里想干嘛 它值一大笔钱呢
What you doing with that in your pocket? It's worth a fortune!
先生们 我一点也不想要
Gentlemen, I have no wish to
那只手表 那只该死的手表被施了魔法
want that watch. That damned watch is bewitched.